

Muneer Syed

DevOps Engineer

sdmuneer89@gmail.com 🔀

+917382323081

Tenali, India

linkedin.com/in/syed-muneer in

github.com/Muneer94 🦪

Five years of DevOps Engineer experience in implementing infrastructure as a code and managing small to large projects from start to finish. Demonstrated track record of implementing infrastructure in such a way it can automatically scale during peak load without any downtime.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DevOps System Engineer

NextechAR Solutions

11/2020 - Present

Canada

· Achievements/Tasks

- Migration of infrastructure from OpenStack to Azure Kubernetes stack.
- Implemented custom domains setup including tls certs with autorotation using letsencrypt.
- Implemented infrastructure as a code using Terraform to eliminate any manual work which helped to reduce deployment time for new infrastructure creation.

DevOps Engineer

LoginRadius

06/2019 - 10/2020 Hyderabad

Achievements/Tasks

- Migration of kubernetes deployment yaml to helm charts which made application deployment easy and reusable
- Implemented service mesh architecture from scratch using istio to reduce network latency and for blue/green deployments.
- Migration of CI/CD pipelines from Azure DevOps to gitlab yaml which helped to do versioning, reproducibility and reusability.
- Automation of penetration testing on kubernetes clusters using kube-hunter tool which helped reduce security weaknesses.
- Setting up persistent storage for pod logs using AWS EFS and send those logs to sumologic using fluentd.

DevOps Engineer

Unwired Labs India Pvt Ltd

04/2016 - 06/2019

Hyderabad

- Achievements/Tasks
- Built a script to encrypt linux containers using ecrypts with the help of mountecryptsroot hooks.
- Configured the infrastructure for high availability of services by using Route53 and Cloudflare CNAME flattening service.
- Optimizing Kernel and Network Tuning so that the server can handle more requests.
- Deployed elasticsearch in k8 with replicas to maintain high availability of database.
- Configured master-slave replication in MYSQL to maintain same data across all servers in order to alleviate system failures.
- Load testing using Gatling by writing scala scripts, based on the reports performance of the application is determined.

SKILLS



EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree

Acharya Nagarjuna University

2011 - 2015

Courses

Computer Science Engineering

Intermediate

Navodaya Junior College

2009 - 2011

Courses

Mathematics, Physics and Chemistry

LANGUAGES



CERTIFICATES

CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator (06/2021 - 06/2024)

Issued by: The Linux Foundation Credential ID: LF-djjscvx4ab

INTERESTS

I have always been fascinated by networking and security.

Listening to podcasts